so the simplest form of predication
supporting hardware will be a
conditional move instruction
in the mips instruction set for example
there is a move z
instruction that takes two sources and
the destination register and the way
this works
is that this instruction compares rt to
0 and if it is 0
then
changes rd to become equal to rs
otherwise leaves rd alone note that
there is no branch here anymore because
this is a single instruction maps also
has a
move n
instruction that works exactly the same
way except
it moves rs into rd only if rt is not
zero
so we would implement our
x equals depending on condition x1 or x2
by doing something like using
comparisons or whatever to put the
result of the condition into let's say
r3 then r1 would be our whatever x1
expression we wanted to implement
r2 would be our x2
and then we would do move n
x
r one r three
move z
x
r
two r three
and this puts one of these two into x
depending on whether r3 was true or
false which means depending on the
condition the x86 instruction set has a
whole set of so-called c move
instructions so for example it has c
move z c move nz
c move greater than etc
where the condition here is determined
by the flags and all of these
instructions effectively implement the
if the condition codes
correspond to one of these conditions
depending on the instruction then the
destination register gets the value of
the source register otherwise the
destination register is not modified so
you can see how we can implement similar
behavior here except maybe we don't even
need to put the condition in a register
because probably we can just test the
condition and then do like greater than
less than and so on on it